[
    {
        "question": "Which country has launched the Rural Community Immigration Class (RCIC Scheme)?",
        "options": [
            "Germany ",
            "Russia ",
            "Canada ",
            "Australia "
        ],
        "answer": "Canada ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country has recently witnessed the outbreak of Human metapneumovirus (HMPV)?",
        "options": [
            "Russia ",
            "Japan  ",
            "China ",
            "United States "
        ],
        "answer": "China ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of initiative launched by Mira Bhayandar Municipal Corporation (MBMC), Maharashtra to empower women entrepreneurs?",
        "options": [
            ", ",
            "Udyog Sakhi ",
            "Faral Sakhi ",
            "Mahila Udyam ",
            "Aasha Sakhi "
        ],
        "answer": "Udyog Sakhi ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been honored with the Gangadhar National Award for Poetry 2023?",
        "options": [
            "Nilakantha Diksita ",
            "Kudikala Vamsidhar ",
            "Prativa Satpathy ",
            "Tishani Parmar "
        ],
        "answer": "Prativa Satpathy ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "How much aid has been announced by the government of India for Vanuatu to support earthquake-related relief efforts in the country after the earthquake?",
        "options": [
            "$ 1 lakh ",
            "$ 2 lakh ",
            "$ 3 lakh ",
            "$ 5 lakh "
        ],
        "answer": "$ 5 lakh ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is the proposed 69th division of the Indian Railway ?",
        "options": [
            "Salem division ",
            "Tinsukia division ",
            "Jammu division ",
            "Waltair division "
        ],
        "answer": "Jammu division ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been sworn in as the 42nd Governor of Bihar?",
        "options": [
            "Rajendra Vishwanath Arlekar ",
            "Arif Mohammad Khan ",
            "K. Vinod Chandran ",
            "Ramesh Chandra "
        ],
        "answer": "Arif Mohammad Khan ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which state has set a target to add 20,000 MW of renewable energy capacity by 2030?",
        "options": [
            "Telangana ",
            "Karnataka ",
            "Gujarat ",
            "Maharashtra "
        ],
        "answer": "Telangana ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country\u2019s satellite is ISRO launching to enable direct smartphone voice calls?",
        "options": [
            "Canada ",
            "United Kingdom ",
            "United States ",
            "Australia "
        ],
        "answer": "United States ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "On which date will the first Lokpal Day be celebrated in 2025?",
        "options": [
            "January 16 ",
            "January 12 ",
            "January 4 ",
            "January 9 "
        ],
        "answer": "January 16 ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which bank has launched a TAB-based digital onboarding process for NRIs to open NRE and NRO accounts?",
        "options": [
            "State Bank of India  ",
            "Kotak Mahindra Bank  ",
            "Indian Overseas Bank  ",
            "Canara Bank "
        ],
        "answer": "State Bank of India  ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following banks is NOT included in the acquisition of 9.5 percent stake by HDFC Bank?",
        "options": [
            "Kotak Mahindra Bank ",
            "Indian Overseas Bank  ",
            "AU Small Finance Bank ",
            "Capital Small Finance Bank "
        ],
        "answer": "Indian Overseas Bank  ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which city is hosting the 18th Pravasi Bhartiya Divas Convention 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Bhubaneshwar, Odisha ",
            "Guwahati, Assam  ",
            "Bhopal, Madhya Pradesh  ",
            "Lucknow, Uttar Pradesh "
        ],
        "answer": "Bhubaneshwar, Odisha ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the theme of the 18th Pravasi Bhartiya Divas Convention 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Contributing to Aatmanirbhar Bharat ",
            "Role of Indian Diaspora in building a New India ",
            "Redefining engagement with the Indian diaspora ",
            "Diaspora\u2019s Contribution to a Viksit Bharat "
        ],
        "answer": "Diaspora\u2019s Contribution to a Viksit Bharat ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is the chief guest of the 18th Pravasi Bhartiya Divas Convention 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Prabowo Subianto ",
            "Lula da Silva ",
            "Christine Carla Kangaloo ",
            "Ngozi Okonjo-Iweala "
        ],
        "answer": "Christine Carla Kangaloo ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which financial institutions has set to approve a $20 billion indicative lending package for Pakistan?",
        "options": [
            "World Bank  ",
            "ADB ",
            "IMF ",
            "AIIB "
        ],
        "answer": "World Bank  ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which bank has begun offering collateral free loans up to Rs.50 lakh for students heading out to top foreign universities?",
        "options": [
            "State Bank of India ",
            "Punjab National Bank  ",
            "Indian Overseas Bank  ",
            "Kotak Mahindra Bank "
        ],
        "answer": "State Bank of India ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Air Force Station base of the Indian Air Force will host the 15th Aero India 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Central Air Command,  Prayagraj, Uttar Pradesh ",
            "Air Force Station, Yelahanka in Bengaluru, Karnataka ",
            "Western Air Command in New Delhi, Delhi ",
            "Eastern Air Command in Shillong, Meghalaya "
        ],
        "answer": "Air Force Station, Yelahanka in Bengaluru, Karnataka ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the theme of the 15th Aero India 2025?",
        "options": [
            "The Runway to a Billion Opportunities ",
            "Fly for a billion opportunities ",
            "Conceive, Indigenize, Collaborate  ",
            "Sky is the place where our adventures begin "
        ],
        "answer": "The Runway to a Billion Opportunities ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Consider the following statements regarding \u2018e-student visa\u2019 and \u2018e-student-x visa\u2019:  1. It is introduced by the Union Ministry of Home Affairs.  2. Under this initiative international students registered on the Study in India (SII) portal can access the e-student visa facility.  Which of the statements given above is/are correct?",
        "options": [
            "1 only ",
            "2 only ",
            "Both 1 and 2 ",
            "Neither 1 nor 2 "
        ],
        "answer": "Both 1 and 2 ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Consider the following statements regarding the Cowpea:  1. It is a leguminous crop which can tolerate droughts.  2. India is the largest producer and consumer of cowpea worldwide.  Which of the statements given above is/are correct?",
        "options": [
            "1 only ",
            "2 only ",
            "Both 1 and 2 ",
            "Neither 1 nor 2 "
        ],
        "answer": "1 only ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "On which one of the following rivers is the Polavaram Project being constructed?",
        "options": [
            "Krishna River ",
            "Godavari River ",
            "Tungabhadra River ",
            "Mahanadi River "
        ],
        "answer": "Godavari River ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which institution in India has developed indigenous technology to develop Paracetamol drugs?",
        "options": [
            "Serum Institute of India Pvt Ltd ",
            "Gennova Biopharmaceuticals Limited ",
            "Bharat Biotech ",
            "Council of Scientific and Industrial Research (CSIR) "
        ],
        "answer": "Council of Scientific and Industrial Research (CSIR) ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where was the 40th Foundation Day of the Department of Scientific and Industrial Research (DSIR) held?",
        "options": [
            "New Delhi  ",
            "Chennai  ",
            "Bengaluru  ",
            "Hyderabad "
        ],
        "answer": "New Delhi  ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "India overtook which country to have the third-largest operational metro rail network in the world?",
        "options": [
            "Russia  ",
            "Germany  ",
            "Japan ",
            "France "
        ],
        "answer": "Japan ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is the third country in the world to have more than 1000 km of operational metro rail network?",
        "options": [
            "India ",
            "China ",
            "Russia  ",
            "United States "
        ],
        "answer": "India ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u2018Abdali Missile\u2019, recently seen in the news, was developed by which one of the following countries?",
        "options": [
            "Iran ",
            "Turkey ",
            "Pakistan ",
            "North Korea "
        ],
        "answer": "Pakistan ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Consider the following statements regarding \u2018Panchayat Se Parliament 2.0\u2019, programme:  1. Its primary focus is to empower women representatives from Panchayati Raj institutions.  2. It will bring together all the women sarpanch across India.  Which of the statements given above is/are correct?",
        "options": [
            "1 only ",
            "2 only ",
            "Both 1 and 2 ",
            "Neither 1 nor 2 "
        ],
        "answer": "1 only ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "The \u2018Banihal Bypass\u2019 is located in:",
        "options": [
            "Himachal Pradesh ",
            "Uttarakhand ",
            "Sikkim ",
            "Jammu & Kashmir "
        ],
        "answer": "Jammu & Kashmir ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which entity has partnered with Stride Ventures to help startups in funding?",
        "options": [
            "NPCI ",
            "SEBI ",
            "DPIIT  ",
            "NASSCOM "
        ],
        "answer": "DPIIT  ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the mascot of the 38th National Games?",
        "options": [
            "Mauli ",
            "Chinkara ",
            "Serow ",
            "Sangai "
        ],
        "answer": "Mauli ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is the author of the book titled INDIAN GENIUS: The Meteoric Rise of Indians in America?",
        "options": [
            "Meenakshi Ahamed ",
            "Kiran Desai ",
            "Siddhartha Mukherjee ",
            "Jhumpa Lahiri "
        ],
        "answer": "Meenakshi Ahamed ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is the author of the book titled \"How India Scaled Mt G20 : The Inside Story Of G20 Presidency\"",
        "options": [
            "Vinod Kumar Paul ",
            "S. Venkatasubramanian ",
            "Arvind Virmani ",
            "Amitabh Kant "
        ],
        "answer": "Amitabh Kant ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is the author of the book titled \"Karma's Child : The story of Indian Cinema's ultimate showman\"?",
        "options": [
            "Amish Tripathi and Anita Nair ",
            "Ashwin Sanghi and Bhavik Sarkhedi ",
            "Subhash Ghai and Suveen Sinha ",
            "Kiran Desai and Ravi Subramanian "
        ],
        "answer": "Subhash Ghai and Suveen Sinha ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "NTPC Renewable Energy Ltd has secured a ____ solar power project from Uttar Pradesh Power Corporation Ltd (UPPCL).",
        "options": [
            "1,000-MW ",
            "1,200-MW ",
            "1,500-MW ",
            "2,000-MW "
        ],
        "answer": "1,000-MW ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    }
]